<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cooklang Blog on Cooklang: recipe markup language</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Cooklang Blog on Cooklang: recipe markup language</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-ie</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 21:27:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Recipe Standard is Important</title><link>/blog/04-why-recipe-standard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 21:27:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/04-why-recipe-standard/</guid><description>A universal recipe standard would transform cooking by providing a shared structure that enables consistency, accessibility, and innovation, much like standardized music notation or programming syntax. Without it, recipes often lose their integrity across kitchens, making cooking needlessly frustrating and unpredictable. While some argue that variability in recipes adds charm, standardization would allow for precise replication, smarter kitchen devices, and a deeper focus on creativity. It’s time to elevate recipes from subjective interpretations to a precise, scalable foundation that benefits everyone—from novice cooks to professional chefs.</description></item><item><title>Generating a recipe graph with ChatGPT</title><link>/blog/03-ai-and-the-evolution-of-recipe-formats/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate><guid>/blog/03-ai-and-the-evolution-of-recipe-formats/</guid><description>This text discusses the challenges of translating traditional recipe formats into a structure understandable by computers. It highlights the issues faced by AI in comprehending the sequence of ingredients and cooking steps, and the steps taken to create a new, AI-friendly format. The piece delves into attempts to design a universal tool for recipe importation and conversion, and the issues encountered. It then outlines a new approach using AI to trace ingredients and cooking actions to create a comprehensive recipe graph, leading to an enhanced user experience and potentially revolutionizing the way we engage with recipes.</description></item><item><title>Practical savings on groceries with Cooklang and tools</title><link>/blog/02-practical-savings-on-groceries-with-cooklang/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate><guid>/blog/02-practical-savings-on-groceries-with-cooklang/</guid><description>This is a list of ideas we think will help you to save time and money on groceries with Cooklang and tools.</description></item><item><title>My approach to automating grocery shopping</title><link>/blog/01-my-approach-to-automating-grocery-shopping/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 19:27:37 +1000</pubDate><guid>/blog/01-my-approach-to-automating-grocery-shopping/</guid><description>How and why I created Cooklang in the first place.</description></item></channel></rss>